who are these people it leads us to our
next story
um which is definitely in line with that
um
so this story is from John kiriaku
right titled American gulag
um
but and it's from Consortium
um which they've been doing great work
um
but it's it's about Western journalists
who are providing breathless depictions
of the harsh conditions facing U.S
basketball star Brittany Greiner in
Russia and kiraku is asking have none of
these been inside a U.S prison
like you know completely unaware but um
yeah we've talked about uh Brittany
Greiner a few times in this in this
light before a little bit especially in
regards to narrative management of the
Ukraine situation you know that sort of
thing
um right but you know
um
so all the major media Outlets announced
recently that former American women's
basketball sensation Brittany Greiner
has been moved to a Russian penal colony
after an appellate court rejected the
appeal of her conviction and the
sentence of nine years for trying to
smuggle a vial of THC oil into Russia
so the sentence is Draconian but it's
not unlike Other Drug sentences here in
the United States but that's not the
point that kiraku wants to make here
what I do want to point out is the U.S
media's use of the term Russian penal
colony other outlets have thrown out the
word Gulag hearkening back to the days
of Yosef Stalin
um NBC News reported that Greiner was
transferred to a penal colony the
successor to the infamous Russian Gulag
Insider magazine said that Greiner uh
fears facing inhumane treatment at
Russia's penal colonies where abuse is
common disease is rampant and labor is
forced
um even the storied UPI United Press
International said that Greiner is going
to a penal colony the descendants of the
notorious Soviet era gulags where
prisoners have been subjected to harsh
treatment and poor conditions prisoners
in the system have been beaten by other
inmates endured torture and forced to
watch Russian propaganda for hours every
day
um
any of this sound familiar to you know
what's happening closer to home any any
of that
yeah okay
I just want to see where this is going
because I haven't read this yet this is
it gets heavy
um these breathless admonitions are
nothing more than a bad joke have none
of these journalists and writers ever
been inside an American prison they
wouldn't have far to look to see that
the U.S prison system gains Nothing by
casting aspirations on the Russian
system or pretty much any other system
including Haiti
like anyway
um
so
um kiryaku wants to point out a
particular
um American Alec Arapaho a Native
American was 21 when he arrived at the
bop's medium Security Federal
Correctional Institute in Florence
Colorado
he tried to hide his homosexuality but
another Native American prisoner William
Mexican a gang member had already heard
that Arapahoe was gay Mexican attacked
Arapahoe extorted money from him accused
him of being gay and threatened to rape
him eventually the Native Americans at
the prison met on the recreation yard
and after a disagreement that neared
violence a faction led by Mexican voted
Arapahoe off the yard
due to his sexual orientation that meant
Arapahoe had to leave the prison
immediately or be beaten
Arapahoe asked his stepmother to call
the prison and intervene to help him
seek protective custody status she did
and he was placed in the segregating
housing unit at USP Florence a maximum
security facility adjacent to the prison
wait what
he went from like
medium now he's at maximum
right so staff who investigated the
protective custody request found a video
recording of the meeting in the yard and
interviewed Mexican who said there would
be trouble for Arapahoe if he returned
they nonetheless filed a report stating
they could find no evidence to support
arapaho's claim that he was in danger
Mexican was later transferred to the USP
and because a staff member only looked
at his paperwork not arapahoes he was
placed in a cell with him
Arapahoe told the guards who escorted
Mexican to his cell and he was nervous
about having Mexican selling with him
but Mexican assured them there would be
no problems and they left
over the course of the next three days
Mexican repeatedly assaulted Arapahoe
forced him to perform oral sex and
anally raped him Arapaho repeatedly
stationed stationed himself in front of
the sales video camera often covered in
blood and hit the cell's distress button
but no one came to investigate Mexico
forced Arapaho to face the back wall
when food was delivered so staff could
not see his injuries finally Mexican
left a cell to go to Recreation and as
soon as the cell door closed Arapahoe
told the escorning guards he was in
danger he was moved to another cell and
a medical examination yielded evidence
of the sexual assaults
um an eternal Bop investigation found
that staff had failed to conduct sell
checks every 30 minutes as required by
uh regulations and his falsified
documentation to show they had performed
the rounds on time the investigation
sustained allegations of inattention to
duty failure to follow policy and
falsification of documents against 26
employees Arapahoe won 750
000 in a lawsuit against the Bop
yeah he should have gotten more more
yeah this is ridiculous
um
like
oh
um there's more
so earlier this year a federal judge in
New York awarded 273
246 uh dollars and 88 cents to a
prisoner who alleged who alleged that a
guard beat him brutally and lied about
the incident Morgan greenberger a
mentally ill prisoner told a guard that
he had eaten a toothbrush and he asked
to be taken to the medical unit
he was placed on special watch where he
was supposed to be under constant
supervision so as to not hurt himself
again
greenberger asked guard Philip Brown
tree for a bottle so that he could
urinate Roundtree told him to wait 15
minutes greenberger asked again 15
minutes later and Roundtree responded
you sure you want it
he then placed the bottle just inside
green Burger cell when greenberger
reached down to pick it up Roundtree
began pummeling him with a baton on the
back arms head and shoulders so hard
that the Baton splintered into pieces
two hours later other guards took
greenberger to a hospital where he
received five Staples to close the wound
on his head greenberger was also charged
with initiating an assault and refusing
a direct order he was given 50 days
in solitary confinement
nearly a year later after greenberger
was released from solitary the verdict
was reversed and he filed his Federal
action
as if this wasn't bad enough we're
supposed to believe that Medical Care in
American prisons is so much better than
it is in Russian prisons kiriaku asks
um
I mean thought so far on any of those
two stories
I mean
this reminds me what's that HBO prison
show called
um shoot someone in the chat I know
um saw in the chat I know some of you
know but um
you know this is kind of what it reminds
me of
um but I think in terms of like Oz there
we go thank you not to be confused with
our Oz yeah
thanks Lauren but um but yeah I mean
we've talked about this before but I
think you know and I shout out to Savvy
for making this point
I think weeks ago it's her stream but I
think
we've been indoctrinated to hate Russia
from like
really I think for me the time I've been
alive you know look at
you know the movies especially in the
80s given the Cold War you know like
there's always this
thing of like Russia versus the United
States
you know and I feel like a lot of why
would kind of like
so I think people feel so passionately
about Ukraine is because
Russia is involved and I think we've
been kind of more or less indoctrinated
to hate Russia you know and so
the idea that what look Yoko is kind of
saying here is like
yeah what's happening to Greiner yeah
it's [__] you know like and I'm kind of
mixed about it you know like should she
be in jail for that long
for having THC no but then again like
you know as a person who travels not a
lot but often enough to know you know
when you're in another country you go by
the rules you know and that may include
you know how you uh use your weed or
whatever substance so if you're not
following the rules you're going to get
consequences for it so
you know like
but the idea of like oh she's almost
like she's a political prisoner
you know in Russia I think this is kind
of like where it was kind of going
you know to make it seem like oh Russian
you know uh gulags are [__] they're bad
you know she's gonna suffer
but if she were here it wouldn't make it
much of a difference she would be still
suffering you know on looking at the
prison population and our prisons here
so
I think it's kind of like the propaganda
in terms of like us immediate being like
luscious [__] and not looking at us and
being like
wish it you know I would argue that in a
lot of ways we're shittier because at
least in Russia they have Universal
Health Care
you know so there's certain things that
they're doing a lot better in Russia and
look I'm saying this because you know
I'm not a fan of Putin I've never
happened he's a capitalist through and
through so he's under the same [__] that
you know that people are in the West
but at least for him there are certain
things that are pretty standard that he
you know he has provided for his people
you know like Nick
reporting on this I no what's it Nick
I think it was even Nick or Savvy I
think this week reported that Putin has
a 75 to 80 percent uh approval rating in
Russia right now yeah compared to like
Biden who's like in the 40s like what no
president in my lifetime has ever hit
maybe 60. maybe Obama at his best was
maybe at 60. I don't remember any
president in my lifetime that hit like
70 or more
you know so
all you want
but
he's at least doing something to kind of
help the Russian people that people are
recognizing yeah and that they're
rewarding him with their loyalty me you
know me and indy have been having this
talk
um about Putin and this will take us off
on a tangent but I'd love if people
would you know
hash that out among themselves on on the
twitters and and all the spaces they're
in do you think Putin is socialist
like would you consider him as so even a
Democratic Socialist
no well I mean if you think about what
his country has
and what he's like how much policy do
you think he's
you know again I would give him the
marker of yes funny like I feel like
people I think that's actually a good
question you know we don't think about
that no you know
communism be curious it would be curious
like put that on Twitter people like and
see but even in the chat like where do
you think
um poon falls on the Overton window like
for me
I mean I was almost argue
like like
poly assault if to our equivalent of a
social doubt yeah in a lot of ways Maybe
more to the center
but this one actually you know but to
some degree but I think then again less
than being centered in Europe means a
different thing here here because
so I think kind of removing it from that
context you know like I think for us he
will definitely be classified poly as a
you know damn social yeah but I think
like in the Europe you would consider
more Centrist you know but the idea of
like your Centrist like
there are a lot of social policies that
even if you're to the right you're full
you know like he's not gotten rid of or
that he's not right like
you know I mean maybe in terms so maybe
in terms of like the world he's probably
like a true Center versus like our
Center here yeah which is more shifted
to the right I mean just as a leader you
know right like as a leader of a country
like let alone what he's done in his
personal life and like how much he has
kept control of Russia that kind of
stuff like right you know but
yeah I mean Warren's saying he's pretty
conservative yeah I could see that but
again compared to here compared to here
sure but I think Europe sure but again
even as a conservative there are certain
issues you don't touch like I'd love to
look at like what policies he's actually
supported over the entire like
you know span he's been a leader but
you know I mean if we're just gonna go
point for point you know that could be
that actually sounds like a segment that
we should do yeah
I I feel like it's a lot of work though
too you know
true but I feel like I don't think it'll
be that hard to kind of look at what is
his ideology like yeah yeah that's not
gonna be that hard you know and then
they're kind of determined like where
does he fall politically but again you
know at bare minimum he is providing for
Russia right now yeah infrastructure and
health information and all that so it's
like you do socialist things
people are going to reward you with as I
said their loyalty yeah so you know so
yeah I would agree probably more
conservative but again relative to
Europe Europe yeah I would say in terms
of here he's probably more what we
considered like a social Dem probably a
little bit more to the right center
um
but at least you know for certain things
they have in Russia that he hasn't
gotten rid of as you said so kiraku
wants to point out another example
um what's happening here in our gulags
um as just one example let's look at the
case of Marquette Davies the 27 year old
was a prisoner in the Kansas Department
of Corrections where Corazon the largest
prison Healthcare Solutions provider has
an exclusive contract to provide medical
care Davis went to Horizon I guess
that's what it is nurse saying that he
felt weakness in his arms and legs the
nurse determined that Davies was
malingering that is making it all up so
he didn't have to work he was fined two
dollars and told not to do it again
months later with the numbness worsening
Davis began to complain that he felt
like something was quote eating his
brain in fact something was eating his
brain it was an untreated fungus that
caused his fission to blur his speech to
slur and his cognition to become so
impaired they began to drink his own
urine
oh
Davies finally had a heart attack
and was taken to a local Kansas City
Hospital a CT scan revealed dramatic
swelling of the brain a day later he was
dead
Davy's lawyer hopes to prove in court
that this was not an isolated incident
but a clear and consistent pattern of
horizon delaying post-poding or not
providing necessary medical treatment
and ACLU spokesman said corizon is
simply writing off the damages that
they're having to pay as the cost of
doing business without doing anything
meaningful to improve
and what about forced labor this is
perhaps the biggest joke of all Western
coverage of greiner's imprisonment the
Constitution of the United States
actually enshrines forced prison labor
right the 13th Amendment states quite
clearly in section one Colin would you
like to read that for the people in the
people in the chat sure
neither slavery or involuntary servitude
except as an punishment for Crime where
of the party shall have been fully shall
have duly convicted right that's within
the United States or any other place
subject to their jurisdiction except key
key word there
um so slavery exists in the United
States it's literally in writing
um so kiryaku wants to write I feel
sorry for Brittany Greiner uh I really
do she got a raw deal she didn't appear
to have Criminal Intent and Russia's
drug laws are draconian
but so are Americas
the media are remiss and pointing
fingers at the Russians while ignoring
exactly the same problems in the U.S
prison system how's that work Colin you
point one finger at that somebody how
many are pointing back at you
great yeah okay just making sure you
knew how many fingers I was holding up
um perhaps they should reflect on
something that Russian author fyodo
doskefsky uh opined on when he wrote the
degree of civilization in the society
can be judged by entering its prisons
he was right
not calling yeah it kind of yeah it kind
of actually kind of took a turn I didn't
expect it to go in that direction but
again you know my thought still stands
it's just the idea that we've been
publicized propagandized with Russia bad
Russia bad Russia bad Russia bad Russia
bad since really like not even since
2016 I can argue since the 80s
especially given the Cold War like 70s
80s you know and it's just a deflection
you know and like pointing at Russia and
saying Russian [__] but then I'm not not
looking at American being like we're
[__] too and if anything may be worse so
again as I said and Kyoko said in the
article yeah like I feel bad for bitly
yeah but again like
like lesson for you all
check the country status on drugs
to see if you are able to take them you
know because if you're caught especially
in there a country you're not
necessarily going to get the same you
know uh license as you might get but
then again I would almost argue
if she was here I mean the same [__]
will probably happen here for her
honestly I mean like as a normal citizen
like you know she since she's you know
an athlete I'm sure it wouldn't be as
bad for her if she got caught here but
again for regular people like black
people we're getting arrested all the
time for repossession here
so what the [__] is the difference
you know she got caught in Russia for
THC black people are getting locked up
here
for barely having any weed
you know
and they're probably in the worst
prisons than the property are in Russia
so
yeah I think you know it's just the
hypocrisy is just astounding and I think
it's just kind of amazing that people
who don't think critically enough or not
able to kind of look at it oh they will
say oh it's what about ISM no it's not
what about ISM it's the idea of like you
know we're calling out Russia
for their [__] fine but you gotta do
that without not calling on our ship
because we're not any better
like in many cases we're probably worse
yeah
far worse in some respects right and
given you know like as I said this
reminds me of an Oz episode yes yeah
black for those kids at home that's
that's their version
right so
the one the one that always got me there
was a scene in that where they he put
like I'm in The Longest Yard uh where he
put like some explosive in a light bulb
that one was always crazy
you turn the light bulb and it blows up
um
like that's [__] up
um but yeah no it [__]
great article from kiryaki who they are
that was good so thank you
um showcase some terrible stories but
yeah
um well and it leads us to what else
America is doing meanwhile well is
America doing that
you know like speaking of us
in the chat right
hi guys
not that Oz he's Ozymandias if no one's
read that poem they should
um it's not the the prison show that's
not what he's named after
um but anyway
[Music]